[roars]
[narrator] Strange beasts and monsters...
vast riches, hidden treasures...
evil haunts, uncharted frontiers...
The mysterious unknown...
the people who are captivated
by the magic in those words...
are called...
Hunters.
[theme music plays]
-[Satotz] Gon!
-[Gon] Where is everybody?
[Satotz] You must lie down.
You need to rest.
[footsteps continue]
[doors clap]
SOME X BROTHER X TROUBLE
[music plays]
[narrator] After learning the reason
for Killua’s disqualification,
Gon was furious with Gittarrackur
or rather, with Killua's brother, Illumi.
Apologize to Killua!
Sorry? But what for?
-You don't know what you did wrong?
-[Illumi] No.
You’re not qualified
to be his big brother.
I didn’t know I had to qualify.
[all gasp]
Friends don’t have to, either.
He gets to choose!
[Illumi] This boy...
[Gon] Don't even bother apologizing.
Just take me to see Killua.
And what will you do?
[Gon] It's obvious!
I'll bring him back!
From the sound of it, you must think
I kidnapped my little brother.
But he walked out of here
of his own free will.
He left, but not by free will.
You guys were manipulating him.
That's the same thing as kidnapping!
We were just discussing
that very subject, Gon.
In fact, Kurapika and Leorio have both
lodged complaints.
The committee has been reviewing
the fairness of Killua's disqualification.
You saw it yourself. Both during and since
his match with the man called Gitarrackur,
Killua behaved strangely.
I believe that there is only reason
that Killua committed murder.
He was hypnotized.
It’s generally considered impossible
to use hypnosis
to direct someone to do such a thing,
however, assassins raised Killua
and murder was commonplace,
so it's natural that he would lack
the proper ethical restraint.
It's worth noting that the attack happened
during my match with Bodoro.
So, it's possible Killua intended
to aid my cause.
Which means if you're going to disqualify
anyone, it should be me!
Whatever the case, it's obvious
that Killua was not in full control
of his actions at the time.
Thus, he should not
have been disqualified!
That is nothing more than speculation.
There's no concrete proof.
From what we saw,
there were no clear indications
he was ordered to commit murder.
And regarding the hypnotism, I would have
to question that claim, as well.
I will agree that the incident occurred
once the battle between Leorio
and Bodoro had gotten underway.
At that point, both fighters were evenly
matched, all things considered.
While Bodoro certainly had
more experience,
it was clear that Leorio
had the definite edge
when it came to raw ability in combat.
Given that it was a fair fight,
there was no need for Killua to interfere.
[scoffs]
And speaking of weird things happening...
why don't we talk about
when you fought with Hisoka?
Mind telling us what it was
he said to you?
Neither of you looked tired.
But Hisoka whispered something to you,
then surrendered.
Weird, right?
I'd understand if he whispered something
and you surrendered,
like with Hanzo and me,
or Bodoro and Hisoka.
We were under a lot of pressure.
Instead, the opposite happened,
which makes me wonder if the two of you
struck some sort of bargain.
If you want to talk about things
that don't make sense,
then your victory fit the bill perfectly.
You don’t have anything to hide, right?
So what did he say? Enlighten us.
I have no such obligation.
Maybe you don't,
but I think you owe it to us.
I don't.
You may find my victory suspect,
but I would say the same
of victory by default.
[growls] What?
[Gon] This is pointless.
[Hanzo] Come on.
Let's just get this over with
so we can all go home.
Look here, pal.
This is completely pointless!
Why argue about whether somebody
should have passed?
If you’re not satisfied that you made it,
you can keep working until you are.
If Killua wants to retake the Hunter Exam,
then I know he'll pass!
He didn't this time, and it is what it is.
But still, if you've been forcing Killua
to murder people
against his will, this whole time...
I will never forgive you.
Never forgive me?
So, what will you do?
I won't do anything.
But after I go rescue Killua,
I'll never let you see him again!
Hmm...
[clears throat]
Alright, gentlemen. Let's continue.
Gon's absolutely right.
It’s up to each of you to decide
whether you’re worthy of your license.
Now, you’re all perfectly welcome
to complain about the results
as much as you like,
but our minds are made up.
Killua has been disqualified
from this year's Hunter Exam,
while the rest of you have passed.
Alright then, I shall continue
with the orientation.
Now, the cards that we’ve passed out
are your Hunter licenses.
This card will allow you
to enter 90 percent of the countries
that limit immigration,
as well as grant you access
to 75 percent of restricted areas
in the world.
Amazing.
You may use 95 percent of public
facilities at absolutely no cost,
and banks will treat you
as if you were a top-rated company.
You can sell it for enough money
to last seven lifetimes,
or you can keep it for a life
of guaranteed comfort.
Please be very careful. You wouldn’t
want it to be misplaced or stolen.
You won't get a replacement.
According to our estimates,
as many as one in five Hunters
somehow manage to lose their card
within a year of receiving it.
Your very first challenge
as a licensed Hunter
is to protect your card at all costs.
From here on out, it's your show.
Believe in yourselves, and keep working
to make your dreams come true.
Well, then we can now certify
all seven applicants present
as licensed Hunters.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
LICENSE
[Gon] Gittarackur.
I want you to tell me where Killua is.
You're really going after him?
-I think that's a bad idea.
-Who cares what you think?
Killua is my friend.
I'll get him back, I swear.
And do they feel the same way?
You bet we do.
Fine, then. I doubt you'll be able
to get there, anyway.
I'm sure Kil just went back home.
Where's that?
On Kukuroo Mountain.
You can find our family's house
at the summit.
[Leorio] Kukuroo Mountain?
[Gon] We got it. Thanks a lot.
[Hisoka] Was that wise?
Giving up your base of operations
like that?
Sure, it isn't a secret.
The locals all know where we live.
Our worlds are drastically different,
a fact that I'm sure they'll all come
to realize once they arrive.
-Hmm.
-Oh, this?
Yeah, it's broken.
[Hisoka] Hmm...
He is interesting.
I can understand your concern
for his future.
Uh-huh.
However, that makes him
all the more dangerous.
I'd like to deal with that as soon as...
Gon is mine. Do not forget that.
Leave him be or suffer the consequences.
I'm aware of that.
I haven't known you long,
but I know your tastes.
So, Hisoka...
what are you going to do now?
Wait patiently...
[shudders]
until the fruit becomes ripe enough
for me to pluck.
[Leorio] Kukuroo Mountain, huh?
Never heard of it.
Do you know where it is, Kurapika?
-Hey, Kurapika!
-Huh?
Oh, what's that?
Pay attention!
Illumi mentioned Kukuroo Mountain.
Do you have any idea where it is?
No, I'm afraid I don't,
but we can just go look it up online.
Hey!
Oh! Hey, Hanzo!
[Hanzo] I'm heading home.
We all went through a lot in a short time
but I had a lot of fun.
[Gon] Yeah, me too.
If you ever visit my country,
just let me know.
I’ll give you a real tour,
no tourist traps!
Later!
Bye! See you!
CLOUD HIDDEN NINJA HANZO
That certainly is one big,
self-assured ninja!
-[Pokkle] Hey.
-[all] Huh?
I’m really sorry about getting
so worked up back there.
Please, I was no better.
I hope you’ll forgive me.
No, I only got mad because deep down,
I knew you were right.
I was just taking out my frustration
at winning by default.
But I'm over that.
I passed, so I might as well
make the best of it, right?
The question is what am I gonna do next?
[Kurapika] Yes, you're right.
I’ve decided that I’ll travel the world,
discover new species
and as a licensed Exotic Game Hunter,
learn everything I can.
-Exotic Game Hunter?
-Oh, hey, what's that thing?
[Pokkle] What, this?
You use it to find
all kinds of information.
Is there anything you wanna know?
I can look it up for you.
Oh, there is! Think you can look up
a Hunter named Ging? Ging Freecss.
[Pokkle] Sure, hold on just a second.
What's Satotz doing?
[Pokkle] I'm curious.
So, who is this Ging guy, anyway?
[Gon] Huh?
‘Cause everything that’s related to him
is behind a tight security system.
You need a whole bunch of codes
to access it.
I think he must have friends
on the national level.
Really? Forget it, then.
Did you hear that? It sounds like your dad
is someone really special.
[Gon chuckles]
[Pokkle] Okay, let me know
if anything comes up.
This is my e-mail address.
-See you around!
-Bye, Pokkle!
We should have asked him
to look up Kukuroo Mountain.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
Well, we are all Hunters now.
Chairman Netero made that much clear.
And it’s probably not the best idea to let
other Hunters know what you’re doing.
-Better to look it up ourselves.
-[all chuckle]
[Satotz] Gon.
Mr. Satotz!
It appears that you forgot something.
Oh, that's right. Thanks a lot!
Also, do you have a brief moment?
-We'll be waiting for you in the lobby.
-[Gon] Okay!
Forgive me, I couldn't help
but overhear your conversation.
As it happens, I specialize
in ancient ruins,
restoration and preservation.
At first, I was fixated on the glory
of new discoveries.
But after watching a certain Hunter,
I became quite ashamed of myself.
That Hunter of which I speak
would discover ruins,
then spend his own money
to completely restore them.
He took steps to preserve the sites
for future generations,
ensuring that people from every walk
of life would be able to enjoy them.
His dedication was impressive.
I'd say more impressive than the ruins
themselves.
His work was documented in manuals,
manuals which are now used
in restorations throughout the world.
The name of this Hunter, Gon...
is none other than Ging Freecss,
the man whom you were just asking about.
[gasps]
I wanted so desperately to meet him,
I did a bit of investigating, myself.
However, the man is an enigma,
and I was never able
to unearth a single thing about him.
Really? That figures.
My goal is to become a Hunter,
just like him.
And my dream is to thank him
in person, one day.
Mm.
That's all I had to say.
My apologies for interrupting you.
It's fine.
Thanks for everything, Mr. Satotz.
-Well, bye!
-Oh, and Gon.
Hmm?
It's nothing.
Just take care of yourself.
Yeah! You do the same.
Goodbye!
-First, let's look up Kukuroo Mountain.
-Right.
Kukuroo Mountain.
There. Here it is.
"Kukuroo Mountain, in the Dentora Region
of the Republic of Padokea
is 3,722 meters high."
The Republic of Padokea?
Never heard of the place.
So, where is it?
Hold on. I'll bring up a map.
This is the Republic of Padokea.
It appears to be a stable country,
so we should be fine.
This country's open to tourists.
That's where Killua is?
It'll take three days to reach by airship.
When do you think we should leave?
-Today! Right now!
-All right! I'm with Gon.
Got it. I'll order the tickets, then.
TAXI
What's going on?
Feels like we've been stuck here forever.
This is bad. At this rate, we'll be late
for our flight.
[Leorio] Hey, pops! Do something!
[driver] Nothing I can do about traffic.
And it's the only road.
In that case...
[theme music playing]
[Gon] Yay!
Hey, Gon! Do you realize
how far away the airport is?
Sure! But I want to go rescue Killua,
and I didn't want to wait around
another second!
-[Kurapika chuckles]
-Fine, you win.
[chuckles] Running like this
kind of reminds me of the Hunter Exam.
[Gon] I know, right!
This is a heck of a lot easier
than the Hunter Exam was!
[Leorio] Oh, yeah.
You got that right.
[Gon] All right!
Race you guys to the airport!
Ready, set, go!
[narrator] Gon and his friends set off
for the Republic of Padokea.
Their destination is Kukuroo Mountain,
where they hope to find Killua's home.
[Menchi] Satotz.
[Satotz] Oh, Menchi and Buhara.
Is it just me or was that
a really close call?
[Satotz] [chuckles] You saw that, did you?
That boy's a mystery.
I feel most compelled to help him.
I almost nearly let it slip that...
the real Hunter Exam isn't over
just yet.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time,
"A Dangerous Watchdog."
-[Gon] Doggy, go, fetch!
-[Leorio] That's it.
-[Gon] Doggie, roll over!
-[Leorio] Oh, yeah!